http://www.tecplot.com/privacy-policy/

425.653.12001.800.763.7005sales@tecplot.comRequest A Quote
© 2020 Tecplot, Inc.
Effective September 1, 2020
Tecplot, Inc. (“Tecplot”) has established a comprehensive privacy program designed to help us respect and protect your data privacy rights. Tecplot is subject to the investigatory and enforcement authority of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC).
Tecplot respects the privacy of visitors to its website. As a result, we have developed this website privacy policy. This website privacy policy applies only to the operation of websites that directly link to this policy when you click on “privacy policy” from the website. The term “personal information” refers to information that can identify you, such as your name, address, telephone number, e-mail address, credit card or other similar information (“personal information”). You have the right to access any of this personal information upon request by emailing our Subscription Services Manager at subscriptions@tecplot.com.
How We Collect Information
We do not collect any personal information from mere visitors to our site. We do not collect any personal information unless you provide it. We may request this personal information when a product or demo is downloaded, for news and information subscriptions, or when additional information about our products or services is requested. Information that is collected: Email, Name, Address, Company, and Industry. When you visit our site, some information is also automatically collected through the use of log files, such as your computer’s Internet Protocol (IP) address, your computer’s operating system, the browser type, the address of a referring web Service and your activity on the Service. We use this information for purposes such as analyzing trends, administering the Service, improving customer service, diagnosing problems with our servers, tracking user movement, and gathering broad demographic information for aggregate use.
Please note that any information that you post to a public discussion group, such as the user forum, Tecplot Talk, is available to all persons accessing that location. In addition, you should be aware that some discussion groups offer a service in which subscribers are emailed a copy of all messages posted to the group on a particular topic. Consequently, if you post a message to the group, your email address may be sent to those subscribers that have indicated an interest in the topic of your message.
How We Use Information
We store and use personal information provided by you to better understand customer needs, as well as to determine how we can improve our products and services. With your permission we may also use this personal information to contact you with announcements and promotions or with questions about your account that may arise. For customers located outside of the United States and Canada, your information may be shared with a third-party distributor acting as Tecplot’s agent, or shared with our European office located in Germany for customers located in Europe. This information is used for the routine purposes of selling Tecplot products, marketing Tecplot products, and providing support for Tecplot products. Information shared with a Tecplot distributor is prohibited from being used for any other purpose and is prohibited from being shared with any other party. You have the option to limit the sharing of this information or update this preference at any time by contacting our Subscription Services Manager at subscriptions@tecplot.com.
We also may disclose personal information when we are required to or we believe it is appropriate to comply with the law (e.g., a lawful subpoena, warrant or court order); to enforce or apply this privacy policy or our other policies or agreements; to initiate, render, bill, and collect for amounts owed to us; to protect our or our customers’ rights, property or safety; to protect our customers from fraudulent, abusive, or unlawful use of our Service; or if we believe that an emergency involving the danger of death or serious physical injury to any person requires disclosure of communications or justifies disclosure of personal information. In addition, information about our customers, including personal information, may be disclosed as part of any merger, acquisition, debt financing, sale of Tecplot assets, as well as in the event of an insolvency, bankruptcy or receivership in which personally identifiable information could be transferred to third parties as one of the business assets of the Tecplot. Please note that Tecplot may be required to disclose an individual’s personal information in response to a lawful request by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.
Protecting Personal Information
Tecplot endeavors to secure your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure by putting into place physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard the information we collect through the site. Please be aware, however, that despite our efforts, no security measures are perfect or impenetrable.
Non-Identifiable Information
In some instances, we collect information that is not personally identifiable. Examples of this type of information include the type of computer operating system used, the type of Web browser used, or the domain name of the website which linked to our site. This information helps us analyze trends, administer our site, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. We do not share, rent, or sell non-identifiable information.
Web Cookies
When you view our website, we may store a small amount of data on your computer. This data is in the form of a “cookie.” It can only be read by the server that sent it. Cookies act as a way to record passwords, orders, and preferences for visiting our site. In addition, cookies allow us to remember you across pages of our website or multiple visits. This saves you time by eliminating the need to re-enter information each time you access a password-protected page. Most Web browsers allow you to erase cookies, block cookies, or receive a warning before a cookie is stored. Refer to your browser’s instructions or help screen to learn more about these functions.
Web Usage Analytics
Our site uses analytics tools to help analyze how users use the site. The tools use cookies. The information generated by the cookies about your use of the site may include IP address, number of visits, page views, and time on site. This information is then used to evaluate visitors’ use of the site and to compile statistical reports for Tecplot.
We will not allow any third party to use the statistical analytics tools to track or collect any personal information or to associate any data gathered from the site with any personal information from any source.
Declining Email Offers
You may unsubscribe from a particular email list at any time by selecting the “Manage Subscriptions” option within the body of the email. All email offers that you receive from Tecplot inform you of how to decline receiving further offers.
Changes to Policy
We reserve the right to change the provisions of this privacy policy at any time by posting a revised privacy policy on the site and indicating on the privacy policy the date it was last updated. Your use of the Service following the posting of such changes or revised statement shall constitute your acceptance of any such changes. We encourage you to review our privacy policy whenever you use our Service to determine if any changes have been made and to make sure that you understand how any personal information you provide will be used.
Contact Us
We take safeguarding your privacy very seriously and Tecplot acknowledges the individual’s right to access their personal data. If you wish to verify, correct or delete any personal information we have collected or if you have any questions or concerns, or would like to be removed from a mailing list, please contact our Subscription Services Manager at subscriptions@tecplot.com.
Note: Tecplot is not responsible for the content or privacy practices of non-Tecplot websites to which this site may link. Review the privacy policy of such sites before use.
Regarding both Data Privacy and Website Privacy, Tecplot follows the following principles:
Notice
Notice will be provided in clear and conspicuous language when individuals are first asked to provide personal information to Tecplot or as soon thereafter as is practicable, but in any event before Tecplot uses such information for a purpose other than that for which it was originally collected or processed or disclosed for the first time to a third party.
Choice
Tecplot will offer individuals the opportunity to choose (opt out) whether their personal information is (i) to be disclosed to a third party or (ii) to be used for a purpose that is materially different from the purpose(s) for which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized by the individuals. Individuals shall be provided with clear, conspicuous, and readily available mechanisms to exercise choice.
It is not necessary for Tecplot to provide choice when disclosure is made to a third party that is acting as an agent to perform task(s) on behalf of and under the instructions of the organization. However, Tecplot shall always enter into a contract guaranteeing the same level of privacy protection as outlined within this statement with the agent.
Tecplot does not collect sensitive information (i.e., personal information specifying medical or health conditions, racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade union membership or information specifying the sex life of the individual). Such collection would require affirmative express consent (opt in) from individuals if such information is to be (i) disclosed to a third party or (ii) used for a purpose other than those for which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized by the individuals through the exercise of opt-in choice. Tecplot treats any personal information received from a third party as sensitive, where the third party identifies and treats it as sensitive.
For details please see the ‘How We Use Information’ above.
Accountability for Onward Transfer
As part of Tecplot’s transfer of personal data to a third party distributor acting as an agent, Tecplot : (i) transfers such data only for limited and specified purposes; (ii) ascertains that the agent is obligated to provide at least the same level of privacy protection as is required by the Principles; (iii) takes reasonable and appropriate steps to ensure that the agent effectively processes the personal information transferred in a manner consistent with Tecplot’s obligations under the Principles; (iv) requires the agent to notify Tecplot if it makes a determination that it can no longer meet its obligation to provide the same level of protection as is required by the Principles; (v) upon notice, including under (iv), take reasonable and appropriate steps to stop and remediate unauthorized processing; and (vi) provide a summary or a representative copy of the relevant privacy provisions of its contract with that agent to the Department upon request.
Security
Tecplot takes reasonable and appropriate measures to protect any personal information collected from loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction, taking into due account the risks involved in the processing and the nature of the personal data.
Data Integrity and Purpose Limitation
Consistent with the Principles, personal information must be limited to the information that is relevant for the purposes of processing. Tecplot will not process personal information in a way that is incompatible with the purposes for which it has been collected or subsequently authorized by the individual. To the extent necessary for those purposes, Tecplot will take reasonable steps to ensure that personal data is reliable for its intended use, accurate, complete, and current. Tecplot will adhere to the Principles for as long as it retains such information.
Information may be retained in a form identifying or making identifiable the individual only for as long as it serves a purpose of processing within the meaning of the paragraph above. This obligation does not prevent Tecplot from processing personal information for longer periods for the time and to the extent such processing reasonably serves the purposes of archiving in the public interest, journalism, literature and art, scientific or historical research, and statistical analysis. In these cases, such processing shall be subject to the other Principles and provisions of the Framework. Tecplot takes reasonable and appropriate measures in complying with this provision.
Depending on the circumstances, examples of compatible processing purposes may include those that reasonably serve customer relations, compliance and legal considerations, auditing, security and fraud prevention, preserving or defending Tecplot’s legal rights, or other purposes consistent with the expectations of a reasonable person given the context of the collection.
In this context, if, given the means of identification reasonably likely to be used (considering, among other things, the costs of and the amount of time required for identification and the available technology at the time of the processing) and the form in which the data is retained, an individual could reasonably be identified by Tecplot, or a third party if it would have access to the data, then the individual is “identifiable.”
Access
Tecplot acknowledges the right of individuals to have access to their personal information. Individuals shall have access to the personal information about them that Tecplot holds and are able to review, correct, amend, or delete that information where it is inaccurate, or has been processed in violation of the Principles, except where the burden or expense of providing access would be disproportionate to the risks to the individual’s privacy in the case in question, or where the rights of persons other than the individual would be violated. Individuals can access this personal information via their MyTecplot account on their profile page or by contacting the Subscription Services Manager at subscriptions@tecplot.com.
Recourse, Enforcement, and Liability
Individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy should first contact Tecplot at:
Tecplot, Inc.
Subscription Services
P.O. Box 52708
Bellevue, Washington, 98015
Tecplot is GDPR Compliant
Tecplot has been GDPR compliant since May 25, 2018.   For more information you can refer to our GDPR compliancy document on our website at https://www.tecplot.com/gdpr-compliance/ or contact us directly at privacy@tecplot.com.
